AAKASH KUMAR

Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh, India 🎽 aakash.kumar733@gmail.com 🛘 9958554654 🛅 in/aakashkumar97

SUMMARY

Team Leader experienced in directing activities of workgroups. Develops strategies, provides training, sets goals and obtains team feedback. Excellent interpersonal and communication skills. Big picture focus with excellence in communicating goals and vision to succeed. Problem solver, networker, and consensus builder.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Applications.

Swami Vivekanand Subharti University • Meerut, Uttar Pradesh, India • 2022

Intermediate.

Board of High School and Intermediate Education, Uttar Pradesh · Prayagraj, Uttar Pradesh, India · 2016

High School.

Central Board of Secondary Education · Delhi, India · 2013

EXPERIENCE

Team Leader

RMSI Pvt. Ltd.

October 2023 - May 2024, Noida, India

- Develop and implement strategic plans, ensuring alignment with organizational goals and objectives.
- Fostered a collaborative team culture, encouraging open communication and idea-sharing.
- Provide mentorship and coaching to team members, resulting in professional development and improved overall team performance.
- Implemented performance evaluation metrics and conducted regular assessments to monitor individual and team progress.

Quality Analyst

RMSI Pvt. Ltd.

March 2023 - October 2023, Noida, India

- Evaluate the quality of annotated data sets by comparing against defined standards and guidelines.
- Conduct thorough reviews of labeled data to identify inaccuracies, inconsistencies, or missing information.
- Implement quality control processes to maintain high standards for labeled data.
- Detect and document errors or inconsistencies in labeled data, ensuring a high level of precision.
- Provide clear feedback and guidelines to annotators to improve accuracy.
- Ensure that data annotators follow established guidelines, instructions, and project requirement.

Data Annotator and Labeler

RMSI Pvt. Ltd.

December 2022 - March 2023, Noida, India

- Accurately annotate and label data according to specified guidelines and project requirements.
- Ensure consistency and quality in labeling to enhance the reliability of datasets.
- Stay informed about industry best practices and emerging trends in data annotation.
- Actively participate in feedback sessions to improve the annotation process and enhance the overall quality of annotated datasets.
- Follow project-specific guidelines and protocols for data annotation to meet the objectives of machine learning and data analysis projects.
- Communicate effectively with project managers and team leads to address any uncertainties or issues related to guidelines.

SKILLS

Front End: HTML, CSS

Back End: PHP, MySQL

Designing: Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

Annotation: CVAT, Kognic

Office: MS Word, MS Excel, MS PowerPoint

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Casual Gamer: Loves to play Open world, FPS, Competitive, Action-Adventure and Stealth video games.

Tech Enthusiast: Avid reader of tech-related articles, Enthusiastic about gaining in-depth knowledge in IT through self-directed learning and continuous exploration of new technologies.

STRENGTHS

Attentive: ensuring accuracy and precision in all tasks and projects.

Adaptable: Adept at adjusting quickly to new tasks, roles, and responsibilities.

Tenacious: Thrives in high-pressure situations, consistently demonstrating resilience and a never-give-up attitude.

Optimistic: Approach challenges with a proactive and optimistic mindset, consistently seeking solutions rather than dwelling on problems.

Leadership: Adept at recognizing individual strengths within the team, empowering and motivating members to contribute their best.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Father's Name : Jeet Singh

Date of Birth : 14th Nov 1997

Gender : Male

Marital status : single

Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : Hindi & English

Declaration:

Place:

I hereby declare that the above information is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

DATE: (Aakash Kumar)